Now we'll look at how we can parse this data with Alteryx.
现在我们来看如何在Alteryx中解析数据
In this example, we're going to use the text input tool,
在这个例子中 我们将使用“文本输入”工具
which is a way to input data without having to bring in a file.
这是一种不需要导入文件就能输入数据的方法
We can simply type in data, which is commonly done when we need
我们可以简单地键入数据 这在只需要
just a record or two to run a test or we can paste records in from Excel or
一个或者两个记录来进行测试或者在从
some other source, which I'm going to do here.
Excel及其它来源直接粘贴数据时很常用 这也是我现在正在做的
Next, to parse the data, we're going to connect the text to columns tool.
接下来 需要解析数据 我们将连接“文本到数列”工具
In the configuration window, we point to the field that we want to parse and
在配置窗口 选择想要解析的数列
then set the delimiter to a period, because as you can see
并将分隔符设为句号 因为你能看到
the period is what is delimiting the components of the data.
是句号在分隔数据的各组成部分
Alteryx will split to columns by default.
Alteryx将其默认分隔为数列
And in the setting right here, number of columns,
在设置中的数列的数量
you can identify how many fields will be generated by the parsing.
需要你分辨解析将会产生多少数列
We need three fields, one for the word data, one for
这里我们需要三个数列 一个给文字data
the first number, and one for the second number.
一个给第一个数字 一个给第二个数字
We can set the output root name to a specific word like col,
我们可以将输入词根设置为一个特定词如col
for column, and when the data is parsed, it will go into
来代表数列 当数据被解析完毕 它将被分隔进
columns with this root name with a consecutive number added to it.
带有这个词根以及加有连续数字的数列
When we run Alteryx, we will see three fields generated, with the expected data
运行Alteryx 我们将看到新生成的带有预想数据的三个数列
in each column, col one, col two, and col three.
col1、col2、col3
In the second example, we see we have an address field
在第二个例子中 我们将看到一个地址数列里
that contains the street address, state, and zip code, all in one field.
包含有街道地址、州、邮编信息 同在一个数列中
However, if we want to count the records in each five digit zip code, it would be
但是 如果我们想要计算每一个5位数字邮编所拥有的记录数量
far easier to work with this data if the address was in one field, the city in
那将地址放在一列 城市放在第二列
a second field and the state in a third field and the zip code in a fourth.
州放在第三列 邮编放在第四列会使数据计算轻松很多
This can easily be done by parsing the data using characters.
通过使用字符来解析数据可以轻松实现这个目的
Notice how the three components of the address are separated by comments,
留意地址的这三个部分是如何通过逗号来分隔的
the street address, the city, and the state plus zip code.
街道地址、城市、州加上邮编
If we use the comma as a delimiter,
如果使用逗号为分隔符
we can divide the data into those three components.
我们可以将数据分隔到三个部分
So let's do that now.
现在我们这样做
We grab the text to columns tool, connect it up, identify
抓取“文本到数列”工具将其连接 设置
the field to parse which is address and then the comma is the delimiter.
解析的数列为地址且逗号为分隔符
And we will split that to three columns.
它将被分割成三个数列
Address one, is the original address.
Address1是原有地址
Address two, is the city.
Address2是城市
And address three, is the state and zip code.
Address3是州加上邮编
Next, we need to separate out the state from the zip code.
下面我们需要将州和邮编分开
This can be done using the space as the delimiter,
这可以通过使用空格为分隔符实现
as you can see the space is the delimiter between these two components.
因为你能看到空格是这两部分之间的分隔符
However, we also want to separate the five digit zip code
但是 我们同时也想将5位数字邮编
from the last four digits.
和后面4位数字分开
And you can see that a dash is delimiting those.
你能看到分隔它们的是一个破折号
To parse those two components within the Address3 field,
要解析Address3数列的两个部分
we grab another text to columns tool, point to the Address3 field,
抓取另一个“文字到数列”工具 选择Address3数列
and set the delimiter to be both a space and a dash.
将分隔符同时设为一个空格和一个破折号
There are three columns that we would like to split into.
我们想将其分成3个数列
And they will all start with ADDR.
它们都将以ADDR开头
As a result we can see that the Address3 field has been split
结果我们能看到Address3数列被分为
into its three component parts.
3个组成部分
And now we can clean up the dataset to get rid of fields and rename them.
现在我们来清理数据库 去除无关数列并重新命名
Grab the Select tool, remove the fields that we no longer need,
抓取“选择”工具以移除不再需要的数列
like address and address 3 and rename the existing fields.
比如address和address3 并重新命名现有数列为
Address, City,
地址、城市
State, ZIP, ZIP4.
州、邮编、邮编4
[SOUND] The result is the newly parsed data with the fixed up fields.
结果是已修补过数列的新解析数据